Christos Tripodis

Chrisostomou Smirnis 48, 154 51, Neo Psychiko, Attica

Mobile: 697 20 28 937

Email: christostripodis@gmail.com

Nationality: Greek

Date of birth: 09/10/1984

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a highly driven Data Scientist with over than 8 years of experience on working with large amount of data and various complicated modeling platforms in FMCG industry. Having developed a strong technical foundation, in regard to a solution design, writing and testing SAS, R and Python applications, I believe that I would be an asset for your organization.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Scientist Intale Ermou 74 Street, 144 52 Athens (Greece) Feb 2018 to present

- Configured Intale's Data Warehouse and visualization for generic usage.
- Set up from scratch PMI (Philip Morris) Datamart and reporting tools. Create a wide range of daily refreshed KPIs addressed to different levels of Stakeholders (Management team, Development Managers, Analysts, etc.) for a holistic view of total Offline PMI Market.
- Applied statistical techniques to address key business objectives
 - o sample balancing for the estimation of Market Shares,
 - o Log-log models for elasticity calculations,
 - o AB testing for evaluation of media campaigns,
 - o Geometrical distribution models for early flag of Out of Stock.
 - o Hierarchical forecasting time series at independent levels.
- Collaborating with FMCG clients to understand their business needs and propose the most appropriate solutions. Explain in simple terms model results and complicated methodologies.
- Clients worked with; PMI, CCH, Mondelez, Nestle, Karelia.

Manager IRI Spartis 48 Street, 144 52 Metamorfosi (Greece) May 2016 to Feb 2018

- Managed a group of Statistician analysts/consultants and numerous projects related to advanced analytics in the area of FMCG.
- Participated in high-level discussions and established processes which significantly improved the efficiency of the deliverables.
- Team leading, mentoring and training.
- Designed, built and implemented machine learning applications for key business questions related to Price Optimization, Promotion effectiveness, Media Planning, Customer Segmentation, Forecasting and other.
- Data Manipulation with large datasets (R, Python, SAS, SQL)

Senior Consultant IRI Parnithos 55 Street, 144 52 Metamorfosi (Greece) May 2014 to May 2016

Marketing statistician analyst IRI Parnithos 55 Street, 144 52 Metamorfosi (Greece) November 2010 to May 2014

Secondment IRI 150 N Clinton St, Chicago, IL 60661 United States June to August 2016

Working for three months to the headquarters in Chicago, I had the opportunity to gain international working experience, interact directly with clients (7-11, Bayer) and their partnerships and also be exposed to high level complex issues in relation to business questions and how they can best be addressed through a great range of statistical techniques.

KEY SKILLS

Technical skills

- Proficient in Supervised and Unsupervised Machine learning techniques (Linear and not Linear Regression, Classification, Clustering, Mixed modeling, Forecasting, Association rules and other.
- Proficient in building the appropriate statistical solutions to address questions associated with Marketing Mix, Price Promo studies, Assortment optimization, basket analytics etc.
- Proficient in SAS (Analysis, design, testing and validating), using a variety of SAS Components (SAS/BASE, SAS/STAT, SAS/Graph, ODS, SAS/Macro, PROC SQL)
- Proficient in R programming. Experienced in performing data manipulation tasks but also applying various statistical techniques via the corresponding packages.
- Proficient in relational database management systems (SQL Server) and SQL.
- Experienced with Data Warehousing Concepts specifically in FMCG sector.
- Hands on Experience in Data visualization tools such as Power Bi and Targit.
- Familiarity with deep learning concepts and applications thought TensorFlow.
- Familiarity with non-relational databases such as MongoDb.
- Familiarity with scripting languages and UNIX environment.
- Familiarity with Python.
- MS Windows / Unix Server, MS Office, Word, Excel, PowerPoint.

Personal Skills

- Business understanding, ability to interpret the results and provide the clients with the accurate insights.
- Time Management working efficiently under pressure in order to meet the deadlines
- Effective collaboration & teamwork in an international multicultural environment, as well with other teams to develop synergies.

Languages

• English Proficient, English Speaking Board May 2014

EDUCATION

BSc Statistics and Actuarial - Financial Mathematics 2002 -2007

University of the Aegean, Department of Statistics and Actuarial - Financial Mathematics

MSc Statistics and Data Analysis 2007 -2011

University of the Aegean, Department of Statistics and Actuarial - Financial Mathematics

MSc Business Analytics 2016 - 2018

Athens University of Economics and Business

Thesis Title; Hierarchical forecasting for estimating sales in Convenience Sector.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Marital status: Engaged

Military obligations: Fulfilled

Interests: movies, sports, travelling etc.